SHOEBUR RAHMAN

Project Manager, Atlas LogitiqueContact: 01717471 383

E-Mail : leekhon108@gmail.com

Date of Birth : July 9, 1989

NID Number : 19892627207628915

Blood Group : B (+Ve)

Father's Name: Md. Fazlur Rahman Mother's Name: Lutfa Begum

Mailing Address: Saif Tower, Holding no 303/2, A. Salam Road, Baharchara, Cox's Bazar 4700

Local Address : Vill: Bhatkura, P.O. Jadabpur, Upzilla: Dhamrai, Zilla: Dhaka 1345

Career Summary

Skilled supply chain professional with nearly 5 years of experience in procurement, logistics, and project management. Adapts quickly to the changing needs of a fast-paced and growing organization. Offers exceptional analytical, process improvement, interpersonal and team management skills. Expertise in procurement processes, vendor management, negotiations, and adhere the policy and compliance. Seeking a position in Supply Chain Management where I can utilize my varied technological, financial, and problem-solving skills.

Skills:

- Procurement Process
- Tool Development
- Process Improvement
- Leadership
- Logistics Management
- Change Management
- Team Management
- Database Management
- Contract Management

Attributes:

- Tech Savvy
- Building Partnership
- Operational Decision Making
- Goal Oriented
- Performance Management
- Quick learner

- Self-directed
- Work well under pressure
- Task Delegation

Work Experiences

Handicap International - Humanity & Inclusion

Project Manager, Atlas Logistique Supply Chain Officer, Logistics Senior Supply Officer, Atlas Logistique Admin Officer, Atlas Logistique May 2020 – Present Apr 2020 – Apr 2020 Oct 2019 – Mar 2020 Apr 2018 – Oct 2019

Key Responsibilities:

- Plans and organizes supply chain activities and ensures that basic supply chain plans are adhered to by all supply chain staff and other related staff.
- Ensures purchase done according to procedures and that quality and services are provided.
- Identify the challenges and flaws within the process, develop strategy to overcome them and monitor activity to ensure developed strategy being followed.
- Communicate with project people and other departments to ensure on time delivery of supplies to the appropriate destination.
- Prepare and review logistical and financial report and develop tools to measure supplier performance.
- Maintains a supplier database, with a price list and a catalog for the mission.
- Support the senior manager on risk assessment by periodic order.
- Evaluates the market in terms of local suppliers and establishes a list of all existing suppliers.
- Participate in evaluating procurement and purchases procedures with the SMT in order to keep them adapted to the local context.
- Participate actively in logistics meetings related to budget follow-up, expenditure follow-up, request follow-up.
- Lead, supervise, coach and motivate the team of 4 people.
- Maintain multiple donors at the same time and ensure the donor policies while purchasing the particular project's items.

Achievements:

 Facilitate logistical (transport Management, Procurement Process) training to 25 different NGOs with more than 120 participants.



- Reduce the operational cost by 12% in 2020 compare with 2019.
- Stabilize the supplier selection process.
- Develop a good network of local supplier.
- Develop tools for monitoring operation and track supplier payment.

DHL Worldwide Express (BD) Pvt. Limited

Retail Outlet Officer - Commercial

Dec 2016 - Mar 2018

Key Responsibilities:

- Driving and maximizing the sales and profitability of the store to achieve growth
- Organizing, preparing, and arranging promotional materials and displays and maintaining accurate Statistical and financial records

Academic Qualification

- PGD in Supply Chain Management (SCM) from Bangladesh Institute of Management Studies (BiMS), Dhaka for 6 months in 2020
- MBA in Marketing from Jahangirnagar University, Dhaka. CGPA 3.69 in 2016
- BBA in Marketing from Northern University Bangladesh, Dhaka. CGPA 3.43 in 2014

Training Summary

- Complete the training on Leadership and Team Management from Future Leaders for 2 days training in 2021
- Successfully completed the training on **Procurement and Logistics Management** (Topics are covered on Procurement, Warehousing, Distribution and Transportation) from bdjobs Training for 2 days in 2021
- Completed the training on Procurement & Logistics Certificate from disasterready.org for 1 day in 2020
- Completed the training on Stock Management from Handicap International Humanity and Inclusion, Cox's Bazar for 1 day in 2020
- Training on Project Management from disasterready.org for 1 day in 2020
- Training on Basic Humanitarian Logistics (Topics are covered on Procurement, Warehousing, Inventory, Transport Management) from World Food Programme, Cox's Bazar for 2 days in 2019
- Training on **Project Cycle Management** (Topics are covered on Initiation, planning, implementation and closure process) from Handicap International Humanity and Inclusion, Cox's Bazar for 1 day in 2019

Language Proficiency

Bengali: Native proficiency

English: Professional working proficiency

Technical Skills

- Computer Skills: MS Office (Advanced in Word, Excel, and Power Point and intermediate in Outlook, MS teams)
- Internet Browsing, E-mailing, Social Media etc.
- Able to type in English with the speed of 25-30 WPM (95% accuracy).

References

ANAELLE CHIVOT

Sr. Project Manager
Humanity & Inclusion, France
Contact: +88 01870-722 131
E-Mail: a.chivot@hi.org
Relation: Professional

N. M. AFTABUL ALAM BHUIYA

Area SCM Humanity & Inclusion, Cox's Bazar Contact: +88 01717-378 174 E-Mail: nmaa.bhuiya@hi.org Relation: Professional